[
    {
      "id": 1,
      "question": "Which of the following meaningful word can be formed using the letters of the word RELATIONSHIP, a letter can be used only once?",
      "options": [
        "Reinstate",
        "Alter",
        "Shipment",
        "None of the above"
      ],
      "answer": "Alter"
    },
    {
      "id": 2,
      "question": "In a row Mihir is 17th from the left and 19th from the right, then what is the total number of candidates in that row?",
      "options": [
        "35",
        "36",
        "29",
        "11"
      ],
      "answer": "35"
    },
    {
      "id": 3,
      "question": "What will be the angle between hour hand and minute hand, if clock shows 8 : 30 PM ? ",
      "options": [
        "90°",
        "75°",
        "60°",
        "50°"
      ],
      "answer": "75°"
    },
    {
      "id": 4,
      "question": "Three of the following four words are alike in a certain way and one is different. Select the odd one.",
      "options": [
        "Goggles",
        "Spectacles",
        "Bifocals",
        "Optical Reader"
      ],
      "answer": "Optical Reader"
    },
    {
      "id": 5,
      "question": "Select the option that is related to the third number in the same way as the second number is related to the first number. 31 : 90 :: 43 : ?",
      "options": [
        "130",
        "125",
        "102",
        "75"
      ],
      "answer": "102"
    },
    {
      "id": 6,
      "question": "Which of the following is a conjunction ?",
      "options": [
        "With",
        "Because",
        "Therefore",
        "None of the above"
      ],
      "answer": "Because"
    },
    {
      "id": 7,
      "question": "Some aliens observe that roosters call before sunrise every day. Having no other information about roosters and sunrises, which of the following inferences would NOT be valid?",
      "options": [
        "Rooster-call and sunrise may be independent cyclic events with the same periodicity",
        "Both may be triggered by a common cause",
        "Rooster-call may be causing the sunrise",
        "Sunrise cannot be the cause of rooster call as the rooster-call precedes sunrise"
      ],
      "answer": "Sunrise cannot be the cause of rooster call as the rooster-call precedes sunrise"
    },
    {
      "id": 8,
      "question": "Yamina threw a die 10 times and got the following results: 5, 3, 6, 6, 1, 4, 5, 3, 3, 2. Which of the following numbers she got the maximum number of times? ",
      "options": [
        "1",
        "5",
        "6",
        "3"
      ],
      "answer": "3"
    },
    {
      "id": 9,
      "question": "Which of the following statements is incorrect as a rule of grammar?",
      "options": [
        "'Shall' with the subject in the second and third person introduces the idea of compulsion",
        "'Will' with the subject in the first person expresses bleak sense of determination.",
        "'Should' with the second and third persons means 'ought to'.",
        "None of the above"
      ],
      "answer": "'Will' with the subject in the first person expresses bleak sense of determination"
    },
    {
      "id": 10,
      "question": "If the bread is toasted and mayonnaise is spread on it then either I will go hungry or I will have acidity. I am hungry so the bread was toasted.",
      "options": [
        "True",
        "False",
        "Maybe",
        "Irrelevant"
      ],
      "answer": "Maybe"
    },
    {
      "id": 11,
      "question": " Which of the following is a prime number?",
      "options": [
        "517",
        "558",
        "571",
        "555"
      ],
      "answer": "571"
    },
    {
      "id": 12,
      "question": "Find the sum of first 90 even natural numbers.",
      "options": [
        "8180",
        "8190",
        "8100",
        "8110"
      ],
      "answer": "8190"
    },
    {
      "id": 13,
      "question": "Find the sum two numbers, whose product is 200 and difference is minimum.",
      "options": [
        "30",
        "27",
        "35",
        "33"
      ],
      "answer": "30"
    },
    {
      "id": 14,
      "question": "A number when divided by 91 leaves a remainder 65. If the same number is divided by 13, find the remainder.",
      "options": [
        "7",
        "0",
        "5",
        "12"
      ],
      "answer": "0"
    },
    {
      "id": 15,
      "question": "How many distinct prime factors are there in 9900?",
      "options": [
        "7",
        "4",
        "27",
        "54"
      ],
      "answer": "4"
    },
    {
      "id": 16,
      "question": "The company’s profits were low and they were forced to __________ staff.",
      "options": [
        "lisp off ",
        "lay off",
        "lay on",
        "lie on"
      ],
      "answer": "lay off"
    },
    {
      "id": 17,
      "question": "A group of fish is called a:",
      "options": [
        "school",
        "army",
        "standard",
        "bus"
      ],
      "answer": "school"
    },
    {
      "id": 18,
      "question": "Which of the following is the assumption for the claim that 'Pleasure is desirable'?",
      "options": [
        "Everyone desires pleasure.",
        "Some persons desire pleasure.",
        "Everyone desires something.",
        "Pleasure is essential."
      ],
      "answer": "Everyone desires pleasure."
    },
    {
      "id": 19,
      "question": "It is a common criticism that most of the academicians live in their ____, so they are not aware of the real life challenges.",
      "options": [
        "homes",
        "ivory towers",
        "glass palaces",
        "big flats"
      ],
      "answer": "ivory towers"
    },
    {
      "id": 20,
      "question": "He is known for his unscrupulous ways. He always sheds ____ tears to deceive people.",
      "options": [
        "fox's",
        "Lion",
        "crocodile",
        "fox"
      ],
      "answer": "crocodile"
    }
    
  ]